Guide to the Doris Duke Papers on the Falcon Lair Residence, 1937-1999 RL.01432
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Administrative Records, 1943-1999
  - Invoices for work performed on the Cadillacs at Falcon Lair, 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Purchase order, work project request form for work to be performed at Falcon Lair, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Nightly "check list" and supplementary instructions for occupants of the Falcon Lair Estate, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Specifications to be used in the erection of Residence Alteration to be built for Mr. S.L. Hawkins by Caspar Ehmcke, 193 Aug 24 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence regarding automobile insurance for two cars at Falcon Lair, 1968-1972 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Architectural Records, 1937-1994, Approximately 40 items
  Includes blueprints, diazo prints, and positive photostats. The records include renovations and alterations to both the interior and exterior of the residence, surveys of the two lots owned by Doris Duke, and a cadastral map of Los Angeles County.
  - Residence Alteration for Mr. S.J. Hawkins - Second Floor Plan (Street Floor). Caspar Ehmcke. 1953 May 6; revised 1953 Aug 24. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Residence Alteration for Mr. S.J. Hawkins, Plot Plan (1 of 11). Caspar Ehmcke. 1953 May 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Residence Alteration for Mr. S.J. Hawkins, 2nd Floor, Plan Schedules (2 of 11). Caspar Ehmcke. 1953 May 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Residence Alteration for Mr. S.J. Hawkins, First Floor Plan & Details (3 of 11). Caspar Ehmcke. 1953 May 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Residence Alteration for Mr. S.J. Hawkins, South & East Elevations, Porch (4 of 11). Caspar Ehmcke. 1953 May 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Residence Alteration for Mr. S.J. Hawkins, Interiors Elevations (5 of 11). Caspar Ehmcke. 1953 May 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Residence Alteration for Mr. S.J. Hawkins, Cabinets, Interiors (6 of 11). Caspar Ehmcke. 1953 May 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Residence Alteration for Mr. S.J. Hawkins, Bedroom Floor Plan (7 of 11), Measured Drawing. Caspar Ehmcke. 1953 May 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Residence Alteration for Mr. S.J. Hawkins, Street Floor Plan, Measured Drawing of Existing Conditions (8 of 11), Measured Drawing. Caspar Ehmcke. 1953 May 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Residence Alteration for Mr. S.J. Hawkins, Playhouse, Revised 1st & 2nd Floor Plan (9 of 11). Caspar Ehmcke. 1953 May 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Residence Alteration for Mr. S.J. Hawkins, Playhouse (10 of 11). Caspar Ehmcke. 1953 May 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Residence Alteration for Mr. S.J. Hawkins, Playhouse, Existing 1st & 2nd Floor Plan (11 of 11). Caspar Ehmcke. 1953 May 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Chimney Repair, Upper Floor Plan, Lower Floor Plan. California Design Collaborative. 1994 Jul 22. Photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Residential Masonry Chimney (A-K). California Design Collaborative. 1994 Jul 22. Photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Residential Masonry Chimney (X, Y, Z). California Design Collaborative. 1994 Jul 22. Photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Music Room B.H. Undated. Positive Photostat. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Site Plan, Fire Storage Room. F.E. MacDonald, Jr., engineer. 1961 Dec 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Lower Level Plan & Section, Fire Storage Room. F.E. MacDonald, Jr., engineer. 1961 Dec 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Sprinkler System - Miss Doris Duke Residence. A.A. Hokom Company. [circa 1962]. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Sketch to Accompany Legal Description. Seaboard Engineering Company. 1953 Mar 25. Photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Lot 11, of Tract 6774. Undated. Photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Cadastral Map No. 145 B 153, Los Angeles County, Calif. Alfred Jones. 1937 Jul 1. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F7)
  - Report of Survey No. 5310 of Portions of Lots 10, 11 & 16, Tract No. 6774, M.B. 70-44/47 in the City of Los Angeles, Doris Duke, Owner. Harvey G. Chapman. 1953 Nov 10. Positive Photostat. (Oversize-folder C1D8F8)
  - Report of Survey No. 4978 of Portion of Lot 11 Tract No. 6774 M.B. 70-44/47 for Gypsy Buys, Owner. Harvey G. Chapman. 1951 Nov 6. Diazo; Positive Photostat. (Oversize-folder C1D8F8)
  - Report of Survey No. 4982, Topography of Parcel 3 a Portion of Lot 11, Tract No. 6774, M.B. 70-44/47 for Russell A. McKinnon, Owner. Harvey G. Chapman. 1951 Nov 17. Diazo; Photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D8F8)
  - Report of Survey No. 5297 of a Portion of Lot 11, Tract No. 6774, M.B. 70-44/47 and a Portion of Sections 10 & 11, T.IS., R. 15W., S. B. B. & M., Doris Duke, Owner. Harvey G. Chapman. 1953 Nov 13. Diazo; Positive Photostat. (Oversize-folder C1D8F8)
  - Doris Duke Beverly Hills. Eckbo Roysion & Williams. Undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder FL1)
  - Main Floor Plan, 1436 Bella Drive. Y. Tom Makino, architect. 1968 Feb 4. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder FL1)
  - Master Bedroom Floor Plan. Makino & Miura, architects. 1975 Nov 17. Diazo. (Oversize-folder FL1)
  - Floor Plan for Miss Doris Duke, 1436 Bella Drive. A.A. Hokom Co. 1963 Feb 20. Diazo. (Oversize-folder FL1)
  - Sketch Proposed Steam Bath over New Tub for Miss Doris Duke, 1436 Bella Drive. A.A. Hokom Co. 1963 Feb 20. Diazo. (Oversize-folder FL1)
  - Sketch Proposed Lavatory & Cabinet for Miss Doris Duke, 1436 Bella Drive. A.A. Hokom Co. 1963 Feb 20. Diazo. (Oversize-folder FL1)
  - Site Plan, Storage, Basement, Survival Shelter (4 sheets). F.E. MacDonald, Jr., civil engineer. 1961 Sep 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder FL1)
  - Easement Required for Water & Power Facilities over Proportion of Bella Drive Proposed to be Vacated. Department of Water & Power. 1954 Apr 1. Diazo with pencil. (Oversize-folder FL1)
  - [Survey Tract No. 6774]. Undated. Diazo with marker. (Oversize-folder FL1)
  - Record of Survey of Lot II of Tract No. 6774. City of Los Angeles. 1993 Sep 9. Photocopy. (Oversize-folder FL1)
  - Garage Door for Playhouse, Hawkins Residence. Caspar Ehmcke, architect. 1953 Jul 31. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder FL1)
  - Rough layout sketch for Parcel 5, Portion Lot 10-Tract 6774. Merle A. Roussellot. 1965 Jun 3. Photocopy. (Oversize-folder FL2)
  - [Sprinkler System, Electricity, Plumbing, Alarms for Falcon Lair]. Undated. Photocopy with marker. (Oversize-folder FL2)
  - V.T.T. (Vesting Tentative Track) 51825 Bella and Ciello Drives Preliminary Landscape Plan. Spindler Engineers. 1993 Dec. Diazo. (Oversize-folder FL2)